A Guide to the Garrett Family Papers, 1832-ca. 1925
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Garrett Family Papers, 1822-ca. 1925.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 45.1
42 items.
Garrett family.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Alternative Form
Also available on microfilm M-1555.
Biographical/Historical Information
Prominent family of Williamsburg, Va.
Scope and Content Information
Includes letters; an account of Levin Y. Winder and his guardian; copies of various Williamsburg Hustings Court records; "A Memory of Williamsburg"; an inventory of household furnishings; deeds and bonds; genealogical information; and photographs of Rear Adm. Cary T. Grayson, and of an unidentified young woman.
Arrangement
Chronologically arranged.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Garrett family.
Persons:
Grayson, Cary T. (Cary Travers), 1878-1938.; Winder, Levin Y.
Geographical Names:
Virginia-- Genealogy.
Contents List
- Indenture between Robert Anderson, Thomas Sands and Richard Garrett and John K. Wright, Feb 1822. (Oversize 1X)
  Concerns the sale of Queen's Creek property to Wright.
- List, ca. 1825. (Oversize 1X)
  E[d]w[ar]d Winder purchases at "Vendue." List of items and prices paid including kitchen furniture, bedsheets, knives, and forks.
- Levin Y. Winder in ac[coun]t with R. R. Garrett, 6 March 1832-14 July 1837. (Folder 1)
- Bond. Robert B. Moreland and John C. Moreland to Mary M. Garrett, 1 January 1841. (Folder 1)
  Concerns the hiring of a slave.
- Copy of Husting Court records, 13 November 1841. (Folder 1)
  Abner Hockaday vs. William Alvis, and Abner Hockaday vs. Samuel and William Allen.
- Sallie Dix to Dr. Robert Garrett, 24 March 1854. (Folder 1)
  A letter from students of the Williamsburg Female Academy on the death of Annie C. Garrett (Robert's daughter). Includes list of resolutions and a badge of mourning.
- Invitation to the "final celebration" of the Phoenix and Philomathean Societies of the College of William and Mary, 3 July 1877. (Folder 1)
- Will of Mary Winder Garrett, 27 December 1877. (Folder 1)
- Will of Mary Winder Garrett, 17 September 1891. (Folder 1)
- Granville Goodloe, Arkadelphia, Arkansas, to Susan Comfort Garrett, Williamsburg, 2 February 1895. (Oversize 1X)
  Re: family history.
- Mary W. Garrett, Williamsburg, [to her brother], 7 March 1895. (Folder 1)
  Re: family history. On back of letter is a brief biography of Benjamin F. Garrett (1820-1877).
- Pamphlet: "The Winders of Laston" by F. A. Winder, 1896. (Folder 1)
  Re: 17th/18th-century English ancestors.
- L.J. Waters, at Beechwood, [to a friend], 27 November 1897. (Folder 1)
  Re: Winder portraits and Washington, D.C. art galleries.
- Will of Mary Winder Garrett, 23 March 1899. (Folder 1)
- Susan C. Garrett, Idaho, to Lottie Garrett, 9-10 June 1901., Includes envelope. (Folder 1)
- Bill from City Livery Sale and Feed Stable to Anna Galt, 1 June 1904. (Folder 1)
  Re: the hire of a horse and buggy driver to Jamestown.
- Sue G. Nelson, Idaho, to Mary W. Garrett, 12 December 1904. (Folder 1)
  Re: family history of Peyton Randolph Nelson.
- Test paper of J. T. Nolen, 11 March 1905. (Folder 1)
  Re: building a phonograph and how sound travels.
- The Women's Club, Richmond Va., to the Misses Garrett, 29 May 1907., Includes envelope. (Folder 2)
  Invitation to tea.
- Mary W. Garrett, Williamsburg, to Granville Goodloe, 24 February 1910. (Folder 2)
- Address of Robert Southall Bright before the Society of the Descendants of the Signers of the Declaration of Independence...delivered at Independence Hall, Philadelphia, 4 July 1910. (Folder 2)
- Will of Mary W. Garrett, 7 March 1911. (Folder 2)
- Susan G. Nelson to [?], post 1915. (Folder 2)
  Letter mentions President Woodrow Wilson's visit to Williamsburg and how Lottie and Mary were invited to the White House. Also family information.
- L. V. Garrett, Newport News, Va., to Mary W. Garrett, "Tazewell Hall," Williamsburg, 19 June 1922., Includes envelope. (Folder 2)
  Enclosed is a transcript of an obituary of Richard Roper Garrett who died January 14, 1855.
- Postcard- E[mma] G[arrett] B[oyd], Atlanta, to Mary Winder Garrett, Tazewell Hall, Williamsburg, 21 July 1925. (Folder 2)
- Emma Garrett Boyd to Miss [Mary?], 24 November 1925. (Folder 2)
- Christmas card- Susie and William Maddox to Lottie and Mary Garrett, 1928. (Folder 2)
- E. Sclater Montague, Hampton, Va., to Mrs. Peyton Nelson ("Aunt Sue"), Williamsburg, 9 April 1930. (Folder 2)
  Re: family matters.
- Letter to Charlotte C. Garrett, n.d. (Folder 3)
- Garrett family genealogical information, n.d. (Folder 3)
- "Garrett Family of York County and Williamsburg, Va.," n.d. (Folder 3)
  Family history of Dr. Robert Major Garrett (1808-1885).
- "A Memory of Williamsburg," (Folder 3)
  Written by one of Robert M. Garrett's children.
- Christmas card of Cary and Gertrude Grayson, n.d. (Folder 3)
- Handy and Winder family genealogical information (Oversize 1X)
- Household inventory, n.d. (Folder 3)
  Inventory of household items, ca. 20th-century. Perhaps from either Archibald Blair house, Tazewell Hall, or Coke-Garrett house.
- Nelson family genealogical information, n.d. (Folder 3)
- Randolph family genealogical information, n.d. (Folder 3)
- Alice Colden Smith to Lottie Garrett, n.d. (Folder 3)
- Photograph, n.d. (Oversize 1X)
  Photograph of two unidentified women. Taken by Homeier and Clark, Richmond, Va.
- Photograph, n.d. (Oversize 1X)
  Photograph of a woman.
- Photograph (Oversize 1X)
  Photograph of Rear Admiral Cary T. Graysonan. Taken by Harris and Ewing, Washington, D.C.